<tools>
  <tool name="think">
    <description>Use the tool to think about something. It will not obtain new information or change the
  database. Use it when complex reasoning or some cache memory is needed.

MANDATORY USAGE — THIS TOOL IS REQUIRED BEFORE EVERY MAJOR SECURITY DECISION.

You MUST use this tool BEFORE:
1. Reporting any vulnerability (use it to answer all 5 Real Impact Gate questions)
2. Spawning a Reporting Agent (use it to verify all 10 pre-report checklist items)
3. Calling finish_scan (use it to verify all 10 completion criteria)
4. Concluding an endpoint has no vulnerabilities (use it to verify all applicable vuln classes were tried)
5. Assigning any severity level (use it to justify with actual evidence)
6. Spawning any Pass 2/3/4 agents (use it to review gaps from previous passes)
7. Testing CORS (use it to verify the endpoint returns sensitive data first)
8. Reporting SSRF (use it to verify you achieved more than a DNS callback)
9. Reporting rate limit findings (use it to verify brute force is actually viable)
10. Reporting XSS (use it to verify headless browser execution was confirmed)

FORBIDDEN: Skipping the think tool and reporting directly without documented reasoning.
FORBIDDEN: Using think as a rubber stamp — it must contain genuine, substantive reasoning.

THINK TOOL TEMPLATE FOR VULNERABILITY REPORTING:
Before reporting any vulnerability, your thought MUST cover:
  FINDING: [precise technical description of the vulnerability]
  SIGNAL 1: [first independent confirmation — exact evidence]
  SIGNAL 2: [second independent confirmation — exact, independent evidence]
  EXPLOITATION PROOF: [exact tangible output — quoted data, executed code, performed action]
  REAL IMPACT Q1: Does this have real business impact? [specific answer]
  REAL IMPACT Q2: What specific data/action is compromised? [exact data types]
  REAL IMPACT Q3: Who is affected and at what scale? [user population]
  REAL IMPACT Q4: Exploitable by external attacker? [yes/no + conditions]
  REAL IMPACT Q5: Two independent signals? [list both]
  ALTERNATIVE EXPLANATIONS RULED OUT: [caching? encoding? design intent? server load?]
  RAW HTTP CAPTURED: [yes/no — if no, capture before reporting]
  UI STEPS DOCUMENTED: [yes/no — if no, document before reporting]
  SEVERITY JUSTIFICATION: [justified by evidence, not intuition]
  FALSE POSITIVE CHECK: [is this one of the known false positive categories? if yes, why not?]
  CONCLUSION: [proceed to report / downgrade to info / discard — with reason]

THINK TOOL TEMPLATE FOR SCAN COMPLETION:
Before calling finish_scan, your thought MUST confirm:
  PASS 1 (Broad Discovery): COMPLETE? [yes/no]
  PASS 2 (Advanced Bypass): COMPLETE? [yes/no]
  PASS 3 (Expert Techniques): COMPLETE? [yes/no]
  PASS 4 (Final Validation): COMPLETE? [yes/no]
  ENDPOINT CHECKLIST 100%: [yes/no — if no, STOP and cover remaining endpoints]
  ALL FINDINGS VALIDATED: [yes/no — by Validation Agents]
  ALL REPORTS HAVE RAW HTTP: [yes/no — request AND response in every report]
  ALL REPORTS HAVE 11 SECTIONS: [yes/no]
  EXECUTIVE SUMMARY READY: [yes/no]
  ZERO PENDING ITEMS: [yes/no]
  FINAL DECISION: [proceed to finish_scan / continue testing — with reason]</description>
    <details>This tool creates dedicated space for structured thinking during complex tasks,
  particularly useful for:
  - Vulnerability validation: Answering all Real Impact Gate questions before reporting
  - Pre-report checklist: Verifying all 10 mandatory items before submitting a vulnerability report
  - Scan completion audit: Verifying all 10 completion criteria before calling finish_scan
  - Tool output analysis: When you need to carefully process the output of previous tool calls
  - Policy-heavy environments: When you need to follow detailed guidelines and verify compliance
  - Sequential decision making: When each action builds on previous ones and mistakes are costly
  - Multi-step problem solving: When you need to break down complex problems into manageable steps
  - False positive prevention: Ruling out alternative explanations before reporting
  - Severity assessment: Justifying severity based on actual evidence rather than intuition</details>
    <parameters>
      <parameter name="thought" type="string" required="true">
        <description>The thought or reasoning to record</description>
      </parameter>
    </parameters>
    <returns type="Dict[str, Any]">
      <description>Response containing: - success: Whether the thought was recorded successfully - message: Confirmation message with character count or error details</description>
    </returns>
    <examples>
  # Planning and strategy
  <function=think>
  <parameter=thought>Analysis of the login endpoint SQL injection:

Current State:
- Confirmed SQL injection in POST /api/v1/auth/login
- Backend database is PostgreSQL 14.2
- Application user has full CRUD privileges

Exploitation Strategy:
1. First, enumerate database structure using UNION-based injection
2. Extract user table schema and credentials
3. Check for password hashing (MD5? bcrypt?)
4. Look for admin accounts and API keys

Risk Assessment:
- CVSS Base Score: 9.8 (Critical)
- Attack Vector: Network (remotely exploitable)
- Privileges Required: None
- Impact: Full database compromise

Evidence Collected:
- Error-based injection confirms PostgreSQL
- Time-based payload: admin' AND pg_sleep(5)-- caused 5s delay
- UNION injection reveals 8 columns in users table

Next Actions:
1. Write PoC exploit script in Python
2. Extract password hashes for analysis
3. Create vulnerability report with full details
4. Test if same vulnerability exists in other endpoints</parameter>
  </function>
    </examples>
  </tool>
</tools>
